Curriculum Vitae Ega Kurnia Yazid

New York City, USA

Contact Information Email: e.yazid@columbia.edu Website: kurniayazid.github.io

yazidega@gmail.com Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kurniayazid/

Phone: +1 (347) 794-2704 Github : github.com/kurniayazid

Professional Summary Ega (he/him) is a final year Master's student in Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences (QMSS) at Columbia University, fully funded by the Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP) scholarship. While studying, he also manages as a Graduate Research Assistant at Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health as well as a Teaching Assistant at Barnard College (BC).

Prior to this, he worked as a Research Assistant at the Department of Economics and a Research Fellow at the Disaster Management Research Unit (DMRU) Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS). At CSIS, he actively participated in writing analytical reports on various topics such as development economics, disaster economics, and policy analysis. Additionally, he assisted the Senior Advisor for poverty eradication to the Minister of National Development Planning in the Republic of Indonesia, specifically in producing evidence-based recommendations.

His work involved undertaking various economic, business, and investment research projects, ranging from the gig economy to renewable energy investments. His research areas of interest include development economics, environmental economics, health economics, disaster management, and digital economy. He earned his bachelor's degree in economics from Universitas Gadjah Mada, Indonesia, in 2019.

Education

Master of Arts, Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences

Sep 2022 - Present

Columbia University, New York City, USA. GPA 3.73/4.00

Bachelor of Science, Economics

Aug 2015 – Jun 2019

Universitas Gadjah Mada, Yogyakarta, Indonesia. GPA 3.63/4.00

Certification

Evaluation of social programs

Jul 2022

JPAL-SEA

Data Science Professional Certificate

Mar 2020

 $_{\rm IBM}$

Certification ID: EAZ88LMHANAE

Teaching Experience TA: Environmental Data Analysis (BC3017) Barnard College, New York City, USA

Spring 2023

Professional Experiences

Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health Role: Graduate Research Assistant

Aug 2023 – Present

Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS)

Jan 2020 – Jul 2022

Role: Research Fellow at DMRU & Research Assistant at Department of Economics

- Conducted research and provided economic as well as statistical analysis
- Prepared the academic papers and policy memo for the policy discussion
- Involved in departmental and unit projects from brainstorming for the research proposal to reporting the research results and evaluation

Ministry of National Development Planning, Indonesia

Socioeconomic Modelling Specialist / Consultant

Jun 2020 – Aug 2022

Assisted the Senior Advisor to the Minister for Social Affairs and Poverty Eradication to prepare the policy briefs and advice regarding socioeconomic issues and policies.

Tenggara Strategics

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

Role: Economic Researcher

- Conducted research on Grab Indonesia's economic contribution. Directly shared the report with Grab's Indonesia Board of Directors.
- Wrote daily media monitoring on the current national affairs for both national and international clients.

Publications & Research Projects

"Fight Against Death Tolls and Economic Slowdown: Striking a Balance Between Mobility and Vaccination", 2022, with Herman Palani, published in CSIS Research Report.

"G20 Toolkit for Measuring Digital Skills and Digital Literacy", 2022, published in collaboration with Oxford Digital Pathways, SMERU Institute, and Ministry of ICT Indonesia.

"Mapping The Wellbeing and Regeneration of Fisher Community", 2021, with Prof. Arief Anshory Yusuf, Prof. Nur Iriawan, Vivi Yulaswati, and Herman Palani, published at Bulletin of Statistics Community Forum (FMS)

"Tracking the Ups and Downs in Indonesia's Economic Activity During COVID-19 Using Mobility Index: Evidence from Provinces in Java and Bali", 2021, with Yose Rizal Damuri, Prabaning Tyas, Haryo Aswicahyono, Lionel Priyadi, and Stella Kusumawardhani, published in ERIA Discussion Paper Series.

"Bouncing Back: An Empirical Evidence of Aggregate Economic Impact of Disasters in Indonesia", 2021, with Esa Azali Asyahid, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Exploration of the Relationship between COVID-19 Cases and Google Search Trends in Indonesia", 2021, with Haryo Aswicahyono, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Readiness of Greater Jakarta hospitals key in mitigating the spread of COVID-19", 2020, with Mikhail Gorbachev Dom, published on The Jakarta Post.

"Game Theory Behind the Dilemma of Homecoming Eid amid the COVID-19 Pandemic", 2020, with Fadli Jihad Dahana Setiawan, published in CSIS Commentaries.

Computer & Programming Skills

Data Analysis Software: STATA, Python, R, Eviews, QGIS

Data Management: SQL, IBM Cloud Research Reporting: Ms Office, LATEX

 $Collaborative\ Ecosystem:\ Microsoft-Teams,\ Google-Suite,\ GitHub$

Awards & Scholarship (Selected)

1. Scholarship Awardee – Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP)

2. 2nd Winner – HackData (Hackathon + Datathon), Indosat Ooredo (2019)

3. 1st Winner – Indonesia Economic Outlook'19, University of Indonesia (2018)

4. 1st Winner – Taxplore Paper Competition, University of Indonesia (2018)